# SARA ZANZOTTERA

# Lisbon, Portugal

www.zansara.dev

sara@zanzohegyi.com 👩 github.com/ZanSara/



in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarazanzottera/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarazanzottera/</a>

# NLP ENGINEER

A rapid learner and problem solver, always excited to find simple solutions to complex challenges. I have experience with Python on projects ranging from particle accelerator frontends to data pipelines, IoT projects, web apps, and Open Source LLM frameworks. I am currently focusing on NLP and Generative AI. I thrive in remote, fast-paced, multicultural teams where quick iteration cycles and continuous delivery are key. At deepset I've been leading a major product rewrite, which improved my leadership, management, and product design skills.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# deepset

NLP Engineer • 2021 - Present • Remote



- #1 Individual Contributor for the Haystack framework (https://github.com/deepset-ai/haystack/)
- Lead developer and product manager of Haystack 2.0, a full rewrite of the library
- Original author of the Canals framework (<a href="https://github.com/deepset-ai/canals/">https://github.com/deepset-ai/canals/</a>)

Blog posts and talks: https://www.zansara.dev/tags/haystack/

## CERN

Software Engineer • 2018 - 2021 • Geneva, Switzerland



- Python expert of the group, mentoring several colleagues
- Renovation of a Python data pipeline for the accelerator's instrumentation
- Closely iterating with the PyQt GUIs team to develop a RAD framework for technicians
- Development of a Java app for particle accelerator technicians to manage low-level applications

Published articles: https://www.zansara.dev/publications/

# CAI

Full-Stack Software Engineer • 2015-2021 • Remote, per-contract



- The ZanzoCam Project (https://zanzocam.github.io/en), a webcam based on Raspberry Pi. autonomous on solar power during the winter. Deployed in 2021 in ~100 huts on the Italian Alps.
- A browsing and management frontend for a canyoning trails GIS database. Deployed in 2019.
- A web application managing bookings for a mountain hut. Deployed in 2016, still maintained.

ZanzoCam project overview: https://www.zansara.dev/projects/zanzocam/

### HARD SKILLS

Python • NLP • LLMs • GPT • HuggingFace • Transformers • SentenceTransformers • Embeddings • Vector stores • Software Engineering • API Design • Open Source • Haystack • AI • FastAPI • Streamlit • GNU/Linux

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Strong problem-solving and analytical skills • High versatility • Rapid, eager learner • Clear, open communication • Sync and async remote collaboration • Critical thinking • Attention to detail • Product decisions • Self-starter • Quick iterations

## **EDUCATION**





**BSc, Computer Science** POLIMI & Tongji • 2013-2016